hello
and welcome in today's video i'm
analyzing icici
lombard general insurance company
limited
the company is engaged in the business
of
offering wide range of general insurance
products
which covers fire marine and other
classes of insurance
i'll be analyzing fundamental data
of this company and then compare it with
its peer group company
this will be a short video
market cap currently for this company
stands at sixty one thousand six forty
four crores
the market cap three years back the data
is not available for both three and five
years
because the company has just been listed
a year or two back
current price is one thousand three
fifty six rupees the highest it had
reached
was uh in last one year was 1440 and
lowest was eight zero five
so it is nearing very much near to its
highest point
that it had reached the current price to
earning is quite expensive at 44 times
and the book value is 154 rupees so it
is trading at a very high premium even
for price earning as well as price book
both
because the current price is 1356 and
the book value is just 154 rupees
so we are paying a very hefty premium to
buy this company
as of today dividend yield is just 0.26
percent
written on capital employed and roe both
are about 20 percent in the latest year
face value is 10. the book value 3 years
back
was 100 rupees which has now moved to
but yet it is very expensive price to
book wise
the number of equity shares outstanding
in the market is 45 crore shares
and its operating margin or profit
margin for the last five years on
average
has been 5.63 percent whereas the
net profit margin earlier we saw that
rather the book value we saw was quite
expensive
written over last one year is hardly
anything
not even one person over the last three
years it has generated
a return of around 25 percent on a
compounded basis
so it has given a good return to the
investors
debt on the company's books is 485
crores
which three years back also was around
485 crores
so there's no increase in the number of
amount of borrowings
we'll ignore the interest cause it's
zero right now showing but when we go to
peer group analysis we'll look at
that the debtor days is 249 this also
will look at later on
investments in the company's books is
around 29
162 crores so out of 61 000 crores of
market cap
investments are 29 000 crores
companies cash holding is very low at
just 26 crores
there are no receivables and payables as
this is this company is into insurance
business
working capital is negative 22 000
crores
that is their liabilities are or current
liabilities rather
are higher than their current assets
the total assets on the company's books
or net assets are 650 for crores
so quite a 654 crores is not that high
high value when compared to the
investments and the balance sheet size
three years back also it was uh so from
three years back it has almost doubled
in size of assets
total balance sheet size is 38 345
crores
so if you want to value it uh in terms
of
or against the balance sheet total so
for
38 000 crores of balance sheet we are
paying
61 000 crores almost 2x then
the balance sheet size
debt to profit is zero point so there is
no hardly any debt on the company's book
so even this debt
that we saw earlier which was around 485
crores
in fact the profit uh profit is more
than the debt
debt is half almost half of the profit
that it earned in one year
so it can very easily pay off the uh
debt using the profit of just one year
itself
and therefore we see here earlier that
there was no interest cost
on the company's balance sheet so this
is good so this debt itself is also very
small
the market cap is around 5.3 times
higher than the revenue generated
in 2020 so this is also quite expensive
so valuation wise definitely it is
expensive because
the returns that it is generating is
quite high
the profit after tax of the last five
years
in total is around three thousand nine
seventy two crores
whereas the cash earned from the
operations or operating activity
is around ten thousand nine thirty eight
crores and it still has a free cash flow
of almost ten thousand three thirty nine
crores
so there's hardly any investments in
fixed assets out of the cash earned
over the years so this concludes the
basic
core analysis now let us move on and
look at next let us look at the price
chart of the company
currently the price is above its 200
days moving average line
on a daily basis so this is a bullish
signal as of today
we can see that whenever it falls below
the
its 200-day moving average that's a good
time to buy
into the company here earlier in march
2020 it had fallen quite substantially
from its moving average
and then it has record back and has been
trailing its to
or moving along its 200 day moving
average line
if you look at the price to earning
it's currently at around 44.4 times and
it has been fluctuating quite
uh quite a lot over the years this data
represents around three years of data
the lowest it had reached was around
35.7
in december uh 2018
where it has around 35 times that is the
price was around 35 times higher than
the profits
so we can take this or the median
price earning as our
target pe or whenever it goes below its
median price earning value or average
price earning value of the last three
years we can take that
as our basic criteria for price earning
instead of keeping it at 25 times fixed
so currently it's median pe or
rather so is somewhere between 40 above
and the current price earning is 44
times
so we are getting it below its uh median
line
or median price earning of last three
years which is
approximately 47. if you have to look at
the operating profit margin
and the net profit margin along with
sales so it has done
a sales in the latest 30th september
quarter
of around 2994 crores and
earned a net profit margin of 13 and
whereas
the opm was around 18.1 percent so we
can see
that it has managed a good returns of
opm and npm
as well as the quarterly sales figure of
the
last three years highest until date
whereas it has been increasing in
in its revenue generation so that's a
good sign
the lowest opm and npm that it had
earned was
in march 19 somewhere around 11.78
percent of opm
and uh net profit margin of eight point
six nine percent
but then since then it has recovered let
us look at its positives and negatives
the company is almost debt free as we
saw earlier company has been maintaining
a healthy dividend payout of
approximately around 18
the negatives are that the stock is
trading very expensive at 8.8 times its
book value
its data days are very high at 248 days
this we'll have to check out why it has
to come
why it is taking so many days to collect
payment from its customers
promoter holding has decreased over the
last three years by around four percent
approximately
moving on let us compare icsa lombard
with general insurance
and maybe we'll take up
since let us look at its net worth first
and then
see where we can compare it with or what
we can compare which companies we can
compare it with
so this is a 7 000 crore company
whereas general insurance is 27 000
crore so it's a
huge against that so what we'll do is
we'll compare icsa lumbar with sbi life
insurance
and hdfc life insurance just to see how
it matches up with these two companies
although their business model may differ
a little bit
one could be general one could be life
and so on so they could have different
business models but as of now for uh
comparison's sake since all of them are
in insurance business
whether they may have sub categories but
i'm considering that
they are into insurance business so
we'll compare icac lumbar
with sbi life insurance and hdfc life
insurance
it's around 5.84 down from its 52-week
highest point
whereas sbi is down by around 17 percent
and hdfc is down by just two persons so
both hdfc and icsci lombard
both are almost nearing their 52-week
highest point
the results for all three companies are
up to date till
september 2020 and annually it's up to
date till march 2020.
sales generated by lombard was around
3 000 crores approximately in this
quarter of september
2020 and in the previous quarter it was
around 2854 crores
that's a 4.93 percent increase in
the revenue generated but when we look
at
the sbi life it's
gained by around 44 percent from its
previous year's quarter from 12 000
crores to 18 000 crores
whereas hdfc life has generated almost
88 percent more revenue
from its previous year's quarter from
8700 to 16500 crores
[Music]
when we look at the net profit icsi
lombard's
net profit has gained by around 35
percent from 307 crores
on a quarterly basis to 415 crores
whereas sbi life has gained around 130
percent
from 129 to 299 crores and
hdfc life has also increased managed to
increase its profit margin
uh on a quarterly basis by 6.1 percent
looking at the sales of 29 2020
against the recent 12 months
icsa lombard's 2020 total revenue
generated was around 12
500 crores approximately which has
decreased in the recent 12 months to 11
600. sbi life has in fact increased its
sales from 43
700 crores to 56 000 crores
even hdfc life has managed to increase
within these
uh recent 12 months from 29
000 crores to 43 000 crores so
we see that ics has not in fact read
the overall revenue has decreased uh
against what sbi life and hdfc life has
managed
sales value is very important to look at
or the revenue that it generates is very
important to look at
profits has increased although from 1
194 crores to 1389 in the recent 12
months
even uh sbi life has managed to increase
their profit from 1400 to 1600
and hdfc from 1200 to 1300 crores
so all three companies have managed to
increase their profits
although revenue wise looking at the
profits
of 2020 and comparating comparing it
with
the cash earned 1194 crores of profit
in 2020 and the cash generated was 3432
crore so this is good like almost 3x
more cash generated for sbi live 1400 of
profits declared but
cash generated of almost 19 000 crores
so someone is interested they can go
into more detail
by checking out the cash flow statement
hdfc
life insurance has also managed almost
7x more cash
so we can see that both hdfc and sbi are
more efficient
in terms of cash generation than lombard
five years price earning very expensive
all three companies
68 times more we have we have to pay
over an average of if you look at the
last five and three years
and the current price earning is mind
boggling 99
times more so it's most expensive as of
uh when price to earning is considered
if you just ignore general insurance
price earning
uh here sbi life is coating at around 52
times
so considering these two now this looks
very low 44 times
earlier when we looked at the standalone
basis this also looked very high
but now when we compare it with svi live
where they are trading
price earning wise this is quite low now
quite understandably because they are
its values or
fundamental numbers are also low
compared to sbi and hdfc
but i failed to understand why would
even investors give such high premium
valuations to these companies
price to cash wise which is more
important than price to earning
all three companies are trading at a
good below 25 times multiple
so even if we ignore price earning and
just purely go by price to cash also
all three companies are generating huge
cash and the best
value is for sbi life at just 4.38 times
that is how the price current price is
just 4.3 times higher
than the cash it is generating per share
whereas lombard is at around 17 times
and hdfc at 18 times price book wise
hdfc is quoting at a very hefty premium
of 17
times its book value or net worth
whereas sbi is at 8 times
even icsei lombard is at around 8.8
times
all three companies trading at an
extreme price to book as well
let's look at the growth in profit over
five years and last three years
lombard has managed 23 growth rate in
its
revenue generation over the last three
years and
in five years it's 15 percent growth
whereas sbi life has managed 11
and 14 percent in fact all of these
three companies have managed almost
double
digit growth rate in their profits over
the last five and three years
in terms of sales lumbar has managed 24
and 26 percent of growth rate
in its revenue generation over the last
five and three years
even sbi life has managed a double digit
growth rate in its revenue generation
hdfc has seen some stagnation
in terms of generating revenue from
where
they were five and three years back in
fact the revenue
has decreased or has seen a degrowth
from where it was three years back
around one person compounded
so there seems to be some stagnation
happening in the hdfc life insurance
in terms of return on equity over five
years
and last three years all three companies
have generated above 15 percent of
roe as well as roc about 20 percent
so all three companies are highly
profitable ones
that is on their equity value
or their capital employed into the
business generating
good returns or profitability is very
good for all of these three companies
in the recent year lombard has generated
around 20
return on equity and 28 percent
in on roc or capital employed
so all these three companies are doing
well written on assets
or total assets employed against that
what is the profitability
is one person for hdfc and life
insurance whereas
lombard values are showing as 19 percent
this needs to be verified because on a
very small
balance sheet size they're generating
huge
amount of profits this can this should
be re-verified like all of these numbers
which
are of the peer group table then those
needs to be re-verified
i said turnover that is how much revenue
it's generating on the asset it has
it's generating around 1.9 times higher
than
uh in terms of profits the profits are
1.9 times higher than the asset it owns
whereas sbi and hdfc both are generating
much better returns on the assets in
terms of revenue generation
of 5 times and 4.3 times for hdfc and
five times
old sbi life insurance if you look at
the five years data of profit and cash
flow as well as free cash flow
lumbar has generated around 3 900 crores
in profits
10 900 crores in terms of cash and
almost 10 000 crores of cash
still pending as free cash which can be
used to
pay off dividend or pay of loans etc
or give bonus or buyback or whatever sbi
life has generated
5 600 crores of profits but 57
000 10 x here this is just 3x
but sb has generated 10x more returns in
terms of
cash and almost all of it it still has
as free cash
even hdfc has generated almost
eight to nine times almost seven times
its profits uh against the cash
as well as it still has a substantial
portion of cash left with them
on an average hdfc is generating around
1 000 crores of profit every year since
last five years
and sbi life is generating around 1100
lombard's profitability is slightly low
at 790 for crores
although net worth wise all of these
three companies are almost the same
but market cap wise if you see 61 000
crores
is the market value given to icci
lombard
eighty four thousand crores to sbi life
and almost one like thirty four thousand
we saw earlier
that tries to book wise it was quite
expensive so
just seven thousand eight hundred crores
of net worth but in the market people
have given it extremely high valuations
of
1 lakh 34 000 crores in terms of
contingent liability
against the net worth 2
100 crores of contingent liability
against net worth of 7800
quite high according to me which is uh
almost
um 30 percent or so so
this is considered slightly high
anything about 20 percent
is considered high but depending on the
quality of the company we can ignore
this
sbi life is around
on a net worth of 9600 crore 1100 crores
of contingent liability again this also
is high
in fact all of these three companies in
fact icc lombard is quite low at 564
crores again
against the 7000 crores of net worth
none of these companies have a
substantial debt on there
even less than one percent not even less
than 0.1 percent
of debt for all these three companies
parameter holding for all the three
companies is above 50 percent
no pledge by any of these three
companies
here data days we can ignore
as we earlier saw that it doesn't have
any debtors as such
so whatever nominal it may be they may
write it up or something like that
since these companies generally don't
have debtors or cust
customers as such so this could be an
one-off
net profit margin hdfc and
sbi both are working at a very low
profitability margin of
around four and three percent whereas
lombard is managing around almost nine
point five percent
none of these companies are paying any
dividend to its shareholders
so this concludes my detailed analysis
of iccr lombard with
sbi life insurance and hdfc life
insurance
if you like this video do share and
subscribe
with your friends thank you for watching
this video
you